Booth Tarkington Papers, 1812-1956 (bulk 1899-1946): Finding Aid C0062
Manuscripts Division
Booth Tarkington Papers, 1812-1956
1899-1946
Manuscripts Division
Princeton University. Library. Special Collections
Tarkington, Booth
C0062
281 boxes
131.9 linear feet
Consists of extensive writings -- novels, plays, short stories, articles, film scenarios, radio scripts -- and correspondence of "The Gentleman from Indiana" Booth Tarkington, noted American author and winner of the Pulitzer Prize.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of the writings and correspondence of Tarkington (Princeton Class of 1893), one of the most prolific authors of his time. Nearly all of his manuscripts, many in autograph form--from his childhood diaries, through the illustrated stories of his college years, to his posthumously published novel--are preserved in the collection, including his Pulitzer Prize-winning Alice Adams and The Magnificent Ambersons, his best known work Penrod, and numerous magazine serials, short stories, plays, film scenarios, radio scripts, poems, and articles. Non-literary activities represented include Tarkington's work for the Seeing Eye, Inc., a foundation for the blind, and his war work in World War II. Illustrations, photographs, memorabilia, documents, and printed material round out the extensive collection.
There is no Box 167 in the numerical sequence.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research use.
Custodial History
The collection was formed as a result of a departmental practice of combining into one collection manuscript material of various accessions relating to a particular author.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Miss Elizabeth Trotter, John T. Jameson, Donald O.B. Jameson, Booth T. Jameson, ,Miss C.E. Murray, Joseph D. Dudley, Mr. and Mrs. Burton Currie, Mrs. James B. Wyman, Mildred G. Burrage, Mrs. Lewis Booker, Bruce Willsie, Betty K. Davis, T.T. Newbold, Thomas H. Creden, and Mr. and Mrs. David Lawrence Chambers. 3 photographs purchased from David Holmes
Appraisal
No appraisal information is available.
Tarkington, Booth
Biographical / Historical
Booth Tarkington (1869–1946), native of Indianapolis and student at Purdue and Princeton universities (Princeton Class of 1893), was perhaps Indiana's most famous author, both as a playwright and as novelist. His best-known works were written in the first decades of the twentieth century: The Gentleman from Indiana (1899), Penrod (1910), Seventeen (1917), The Magnificent Ambersons (1918), and Alice Adams (1921). The last two won Pulitzer Prizes. In his work he showed an appreciation of the development of his native city, and an amiable understanding of the real and imagined problems of young people. He was an early member of The Dramatic Club, founded in 1889, and often wrote plays and directed and acted in its productions.
American drama -- 20th century.; American fiction -- 19th century.; American fiction -- 20th century.; Short stories, American -- 20th century.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Propaganda.; World War, 1939-1945 -- War work -- United States.; American diaries -- 20th century.; Drawings -- 19th century.; Fiction -- 20th century.; Manuscripts (for publication).; Radio scripts -- United States.; Dramatists, American -- 20th century.; Novelists, American -- 20th century.; College of New Jersey (Princeton, N.J.). Class of 1893.; Seeing Eye, Inc.; Trotter, Elizabeth Stanley
- Series 1: Writings, 1893-1986; 167 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  Collection is open for research use.
  Scope and Contents
  Consists of writings of Booth Tarkington, including novels, plays, short stories, radio scripts, and poems, as well as others.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged into twenty-two subseries: Novels/Novellas, Serials, Short Stories, Short Story Collections, Plays, Film Scenarios, Radio Scripts, Poems/Songs/Verses, Operatta, Non-Fiction Books, Articles, Speeches, Art Notes, Juvenilia, Miscellaneous Works, and Fragments/Notes/Unfinished/Untitled/Unidentified.
  - Subseries 1A: Novels/Novellas, 1904-1945; 69 boxes
    Consists of manuscripts for novels and novellas of Booth Tarkington, including Alice Adams, Cherry, Gentle Julia as well as others.
    Not arranged according to any arrangement scheme.
    - Alice Adams, 1921 February-May; 2 boxes
      - Magazine Galleys/Proofs, Pictorial Review, 1st Installment, 1921 February; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Magazine Galleys/Proofs, Pictorial Review, 2nd Installment, 1921 March; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Magazine Galleys/Proofs, Pictorial review, 3rd Installment, 1921 April; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Magazine Galleys/Proofs, Pictorial Review, 4th (Final) Installment, 1921 May; 1 folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Chapters 1-6 (pp. 1-129), undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Chapters 7-12 (pp. 130-273), undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Chapters 8-19 (pp. 131-409), undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Chapters 20-24 (pp. 410-538), undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Typed Manuscript, Chapters 1-13 (pp. 1-141), undated; 1 folder Carbon with holograph corrections (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Typed Manuscript, Chapters 14-25 (pp. 142-280), undated; 1 folder Carbon with holograph corrections (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Manuscripts [in Elizabeth Trotter's hand], and Typed Description of Novel, undated; 1 folder (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bailey Fount: 1st Draft from Magazine Novelette into Book, undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (carbon) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Beasley and the Hunchbergs: pp. 1-34, Cosmopolitan, 1905 December; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Beasley's Christmas Party, undated; 4 folders Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 4, Folder 2-5)
    - The Beautiful Lady, 1904; 1 folder Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Cherry, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Bound Copy from Harper's Magazine, 1901; 1 folder With holograph corrections (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Chapter 1, dates not examined; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Chapters 1-3, dates not examined; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Chapters 1-7 (except chapter 4), undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Chapters 8-15 (end), undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Chapters 5-15 and 14-15, undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Chapters 1-15, undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - AMs and TMs, chapters 5-15, dates not examined; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous Pages, undated; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Notes on Writing Cherry), undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Claire Ambler; Raona section, 1927; 1 folder Typed manuscript and photostat (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Conquest of Canaan, undated; 6 folders (Box 7, Folder 2-7)
      Includes magazine galleys, fragments, typed and autograph manuscripts, and typed manuscript of preface.
    - "Fame at Fifteen,"Saturday Evening Post, 1938 February 19; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Later expanded to The Fighting Littles.
    - "The Jabjam Moto Trip," Saturday Evening Post, 1939 December 3; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - The Fighting Littles, undated; 8 folders Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 8, Folder 3-10)
    - "Now, Ripley, Please", undated; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Later revised to become chapters 1-3 for The Fighting Littles.
    - "Almost a What?", Saturday Evening Post, 1937 June 26; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Later revised to become chapters 5-8 in The Fighting Littles.
    - "Peppah, More Peppah!", Saturday Evening Post, 1937 October 30; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Also includes autograph notes.
      Later revised to become chapters 9-14 in The Fighting Littles.
    - "Sinful Dadda Little," Saturday Evening Post, 1939 July 22; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Later revised to become 25-27 (part) and 28 (part) in The Fighting Littles.
    - "Fame at Fifteen," Saturday Evening Post, 1938 February 19; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Later revised to become chapters 19-22 (part) of The Fighting Littles.
    - The Fighting Littles, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 7 folders (Box 10, Folder 1-7)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - The Flirt, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Notes, 1913; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Chapters 1-12, undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Chapters 13-24, undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Typescript, Chapters 1-6, undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Typescript, Chapters 7-14, undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - TMs, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
    - Gentle Julia, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1922; 3 folders (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
      - Manuscript, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - The Gentleman from Indiana, 1899; 2 boxes
      - Galleys, McClure's, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - First Draft, undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Fragment, "The Poet in love", undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Autograph Fragment, undated; 1 folder (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Autograph and Typed Manuscripts, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 15, Folder 6-8)
      - Autograph and Typed Manuscripts, dates not examined; 6 folders (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
    - The Guest of Quesnay, 1904-1905; 3 folders Autograph manuscript (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
    - The Heritage of Thatcher Ade: Manuscript, undated; 5 folders (Box 18, Folder 1-5)
    - "The Man of the Family," in Saturday Evening Post, 1941 November-December 21; 2 folders Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
      Later published as the novel The Heritage of Thatcher Ade.
    - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - The Heritage of Thatcher Ade, dates not examined; 3 boxes
      - Autograph and Typed Manuscripts, undated; 7 folders (Box 19, Folder 3-9)
      - Autograph Manuscript, dates not examined; 6 folders (Box 20, Folder 1-6)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Page Proofs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - His Own People, 1907; 4 folders (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
    - His Word of Honor (unpublished), 1905; 1 folder Typed manuscript, proofs (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Image of Josephine, 1945; 4 boxes
      - Typed and autograph manuscripts, 1945; 2 folders (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
      - "The Lovely Hellion," in The American Magazine, undated; 3 folders (Box 24, Folder 3-5)
        Later published as the book Image of Josephine.
      - "The Lovely Hellion", undated; 2 folders Typed manuscript (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
      - Autograph and Typed Manuscripts, dates not examined; 4 folders (Box 25, Folder 3-6)
      - Autograph and Typed Manuscripts, dates not examined; 6 folders (Box 26, Folder 1-6)
      - Autograph and Typed Manuscripts, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - On the Literary Guide's Selection of Image of Josephine), undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - "Why `Image of Josephine'?" in Wings, 1945; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - "The Hardest Wife to Be," Ladies Home Journal, 1942 June-September; 7 folders Typed manuscript (Box 28, Folder 1-7)
      Later expanded to the novel Kate Fennigate.
    - Kate Fennigate, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 10 folders (Box 29, Folder 1-10)
      - Typed Manuscript, 1943; 10 folders (Box 30, Folder 1-10)
      - Jacket Blurb, undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Printed Material, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Typed Manuscript on the Book (not written by Tarkington), undated; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Little Orvie, dates not examined; 3 boxes
      - "The Terrible Shyness of Orvie Stone," in the Saturday Evening Post, 1933 June 24; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - "Little Marie from Kansas City," in the Saturday Evening Post, 1933 June 24; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - "Little Orvie's New Dog Ralph," in the Saturday Evening Post, 1933 September 30; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - "Little Orvie's Grandma's Error," in the Saturday Evening Post, 1933 October 28; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - "Little Orvie's and Big Birdie," in the Saturday Evening Post3, 1933 October 28; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - "Little Orvie's Fixation," in the Saturday Evening Post, 1934 February 17; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - "Little Orvie and Boydie Boy," in the Saturday Evening Post, 1934 April 21; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - "Here Comes The Page!" in Saturday Evening Post, 1934 May 19; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - "Love's Almost Very First Dawn," in the Saturday Evenig Post, 1934 July 28; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - "Little Orvie's Little Girl," in Saturday Evening Post, 1934 September 15; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - "Blue Milk," in Saturday Evening Post, 1934 October 20; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - "The Lovingest Cousin," in Saturday Evening Post, 1934 November 3; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Notes, undated; 1 folder Autograph manuscript (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - The Lorenzo Bunch, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Typed Manuscript, 1936; 10 folders (Box 34, Folder 1-10)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 7 folders (Box 35, Folder 1-7)
    - Mary's Neck, 1930 March-September; 2 boxes
      - Notes, 1932; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - "Longansville and Mary's Neck": Manuscript, Saturday Evening Post, 1929 February 23; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - "Hour of Peril": Manuscript, Hearst's International, 1930 July; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - "Importance at the Neck": Manuscript, Saturday Evening Post, 1929 March 9; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - "Mr. Massey and Modernism": Saturday Evening Post, 1929 April 13; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - "Being Chairman at the Neck," The American Magazine, 1930 March; 2 folders Typed manuscript (Box 36, Folder 6-7)
      - "The Neck and Bush Thing": Manuscript, Saturday Evening Post, 1929 March 23; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - "Talk at Mary's Neck": Manuscript, The American Magazine, 1930 April; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - "The Distinguished Visitor": Manuscript, Good Housekeeping, 1930 September; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - "In a Silver Frame": Manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Typed Manuscript, 1932; 3 folders (Box 37, Folder 1-3)
    - The Magnificent Ambersons, dates not examined; 3 boxes
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1918; 5 folders (Box 38, Folder 1-5)
      - Typed Manuscript, 1918; 7 folders (Box 39, Folder 1-7)
      - Loose Page (p. 224), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 40, Folder 1-3)
    - The Midlander, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1924; 4 folders (Box 41, Folder 1-4)
      - Typed Manuscript (1924), 2 folders (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
    - Mirthful Haven: Galleys, 1930; 2 folders (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
    - Monsieur Beaucaire, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1896-1900; 2 folders (Box 43, Folder 1-2)
        Manuscript dated 1896, published 1900.
      - Manuscript, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Galley Proof, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Penrod, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1914; 9 folders (Box 44, Folder 1-9)
      - Manuscript, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Magazine Clippings with Corrections, Creating Novel from Stories, undated; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Galley, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 44, Folder 12-13)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 9 folders (Box 45, Folder 1-9)
    - Onki Rupe Collins: Typed Manuscript, undated; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Penrod and Sam, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Autograph Manuscripts, Signed, 1916; 4 folders (Box 46, Folder 1-4)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 5 folders (Box 46, Folder 5-9)
    - Penrod Jashber, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1929; 3 folders (Box 47, Folder 1-3)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 47, Folder 4-6)
    - The Plutocrat, dates not examined; 3 boxes
      - Typed Manuscript, 1927; 4 folders (Box 48, Folder 1-4)
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1926; 1 box (Box custom)
    - Presenting Lily Mars, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Manuscript, 1933; 5 folders (Box 49, Folder 1-5)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 49, Folder 6-7)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 50, Folder 1-3)
      - Manuscript, undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Ramsey Milholland, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Typed Manuscript, 1919; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Rumbin Galleries, dates not examined; 3 boxes
      - Manuscript, 1937; 3 folders (Box 52, Folder 1-3)
      - Manuscript, undated; 3 folders Typed manuscript (Box 52, Folder 4-6)
      - Manuscript, undated; 5 folders Typed manuscript (Box 53, Folder 1-5)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - "Genesis of Rumbin Galleries": Manuscript, undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Seventeen, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1916; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 1)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Autograph Manuscript, dates not examined; 4 folders (Box 55, Folder 3-6)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 55, Folder 7-9)
      - Typed Manuscript (Introduction to 1932 Edition), undated; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 10)
      - Manuscript, Foreword, undated; 1 folder (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - The Show Piece, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Manuscript, 1947; 8 folders (Box 56, Folder 1-8)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 8 folders (Box 57, Folder 1-8)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 9)
      - Introduction by Mrs. Susannah Tarkington, undated; 1 folder (Box 57, Folder 10)
        Published posthumously.
    - Walterson in Three Selected Short Novels, 1947; 1 folder Autograph and typed manuscripts (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 58, Folder 2-4)
    - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 5 folders (Box 58, Folder 5-9)
    - Uncertain Molly Collicut in Three Selected Short Novels: Manuscript, undated; 3 folders (Box 59, Folder 1-3)
    - Uncertain Molly Collicut in Three Selected Short Novels, undated; 1 folder Typed manuscript (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - "O Woman! Uncertain Mrs. Collicut," Pictorial Review, 1938 December; 3 folders Typed manuscript (Box 60, Folder 1-3)
    - Rennie Peddigoe in Three Selected Short Novels: Manuscript, undated; 3 folders (Box 61, Folder 1-3)
    - Rennie Peddigoe in Three Selected Short Novels: Manuscript, undated; 3 folders (Box 61, Folder 4-6)
    - Rennie Peddigoe in Three Selected Short Novels: Galleys, Proofs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - The Turmoil, 1915; 5 folders Typed manuscript (Box 62, Folder 1-5)
    - The Two Vanrevels, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Galleys from Serial in McClure's, 1902; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Autograph Manuscript, Signed, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Notes of Criticism by Tarkington's Father, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Autograph Manuscript, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Manuscript, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 63, Folder 5-7)
      - Autograph Manuscript, dates not examined; 5 folders (Box 63, Folder 8-12)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 4 folders (Box 64, Folder 1-4)
    - Wanton Molly, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Manuscript, 1932; 3 folders (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
      - Galley Proofs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Women, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1925; 10 folders (Box 66, Folder 1-10)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 66, Folder 11-13)
    - Young Mrs. Greeley, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Autograph Manuscript, 1929; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Manuscript, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 1B: Serials, 1941; 11 boxes
    Consists of manuscripts for serials, including "As I Seem to Me," "This Boy Joe," and "Outline Sketch For Consideration," as well as others.
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - As I Seem to Me, 1941; 2 boxes
      - Notes, in the Saturday Evening Post, 1941; 4 folders Typed and autograph manuscripts (Box 68, Folder 1-4)
      - Manuscript, undated; 4 folders Typed manuscript (Box 69, Folder 1-4)
      - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Galleys, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Photographs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - The Divine Evade, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Manuscript (Good Housekeeping), 1933-1934; 4 folders (Box 70, Folder 1-4)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 70, Folder 5-7)
    - High Summer, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Manuscript, 1931; 3 folders (Box 71, Folder 1-3)
      - Typed Manuscripts, Signed, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 71, Folder 4-5)
    - Otherwise Kitty Swift, dates not examined; 2 boxes
      - Manuscript, 1938; 5 folders (Box 72, Folder 1-5)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 4 folders (Box 73, Folder 1-4)
      - Typed Manuscript with Letter to Brandt, undated; 1 folder (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 2 folders (Box 73, Folder 6-7)
    - Pretty Twenty, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Manuscript, 1932; 3 folders (Box 74, Folder 1-3)
      - Typed Manuscript, dates not examined; 3 folders (Box 74, Folder 4-6)
    - Some People Have All the Luck: Typed Manuscript, 1946; 1 folder (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - This Boy Joe, dates not examined; 2 boxes